swarb.co.uk 2003-12-14

# Privacy Statement, www.swarb.co.uk, op, us, , law-bytes@swarb.co.uk, David Swarbrick, Solicitor, Wrigley Claydon

We provide Legal Services through the firm Wrigley Claydon. Protecting your privacy and your personal data is an important aspect of the way we create, organise and implement our activities on-line and off-line. 

This statement refers to this particular site (www.swarb.co.uk) only. 

We are based in England. 

| **Contacting Us**  
---  
Organisation| Wrigley Claydon  
Address| 29/33 Union Street  
| Oldham  
| Greater Manchester  
| OL1 1HH  
| England  
URL| http://www.swarb.co.uk/  
E-Mail| david.swarbrick@lawindexpro.co.uk or david.swarbrick@wrigleyclaydon.com  
Physical Location| England  
**Privacy Support**  
---  
  
Privacy Compliance 

Our privacy policy is compliant with the following national instruments: 

  1. Data Protection Act 1998 
  2. Law Society and Solicitors Professional Codes of Practice and Principles 

We are committed to a compliance procedure that attests that our privacy policy with respect to the above privacy instruments. 

Linkage Characteristics 

Purpose Specification and Data Collection 

You can access our Web site home page and browse our site 

http://www.swarb.co.uk without disclosing personal data, save to the extent that that is revealed in the usual activity logs created by our ISP. 

We collect your personal data only with your knowledge and consent. 

Cookies 

We do not use cookies on our Web site. 

All our employees and processors who have access to your personal data and are associated with the processing of that data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of your personal data. 

Visitor Choice 

Disclosure 

We do not disclose your personal to any third party. 

We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to State institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. 

Individual Participation/Access 

You can ask us whether we are keeping personal data about you, by sending an email to david.swarbrick@lawindexpro.co.uk, or by sending postal mail to the above address: 

A reasonable charge may be made for access to any particular data set. 

Upon request, which you can indicate we will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data which we keep about you. 

We allow you to change the data that we hold about you. 

Security 

We have implemented technology and security policies, rules and measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from unauthorised access, improper use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction, accidental loss. 

Privacy Compliance details 

The Privacy Principles of the OECD Guidelines 

  1. Collection Limitation Principle 

There should be limits to the collection of personal data and any such data should be obtained by lawful and fair means and, where appropriate, with the knowledge or consent of the data subject. 

  2. Data Quality Principle 

Personal data should be relevant to the purposes for which they are to be used, and, to the extent necessary for those purposes, should be accurate, complete and kept up-to-date. 

  3. Purpose Specification Principle 

The purposes for which personal data are collected should be specified not later than at the time of data collection and the subsequent use limited to the fulfilment of those purposes or such others as are not incompatible with those purposes and as are specified on each occasion of change of purpose. 

  4. Use Limitation Principle 

Personal data should not be disclosed, made available or otherwise used for purposes other than those specified in accordance with Paragraph 9 [Purpose Specification Principle] of the OECD Privacy Guidelines except: 

    1. with the consent of the data subject; or 
    2. by the authority of law. 
  5. Security Safeguards Principle 

Personal data should be protected by reasonable security safeguards against such risks as loss or unauthorised access, destruction, use, modification or disclosure of data. 

  6. Openness Principle 

There should be a general policy of openness about developments, practices and policies with respect to personal data. Means should be readily available of establishing the existence and nature of personal data, and the main purposes of their use, as well as the identity and usual residence of the Data Controller. 

  7. Individual Participation Principle 

An individual should have the right: 

    1. to obtain from a data controller, or otherwise, confirmation of whether or not the data controller has data relating to him; 
    2. to have communicated to him, data relating to him within a reasonable time; at a charge, if any, that is not excessive; in a reasonable manner; and in a form that is readily intelligible to him; 
    3. to be given reasons if a request made under subparagraphs(a) and (b) is denied, and to be able to challenge such denial; and 
    4. to challenge data relating to him and, if the challenge is successful to have the data erased, rectified, completed or amended. 
  8. Accountability Principle 

A Data Controller should be accountable for complying with measures which give effect to the principles stated above. 

Our ISP collects an audit trail of page calls which log is available to us. It states (in standard Microsoft IS format), the date and time, the IP address of visitors to the site, the method used, the file requested (the 'hit') and the result of the call. 

We analyse that information to assist in maintaining and assessing the site. 

* * *

This is our privacy policy: 

  1. As solicitors, we are covered by strict codes regarding privacy and confidentiality. Thses rules are both those set out in We will abide by those rules, but for the sake of completeness, add the following rules. 
  2. Save where stated above, we do not monitor this site to seek to establish the identity of visitors to it. 
  3. We will store no cookies or other record of your visit on your computers, save to teh extent that your browser does this for you. 
  4. We will treat e-mails forwarded to us with respect and in confidence. Please note that we cannot promise confidentiality before the point at which your e-mail arrives at our local computer. 
  5. We will not pass on to others any information received by us from you via this site, including any identity or e-mail address. 
  6. We will follow the Data Protection Principles so far as they relate to our on-line activities.
